[{"question":"Which of the following is a correct match of a phylum with its three examples?","a":"Platyhelminthes-Planaria, Schistosoma, Enterobius","b":"Mollusca Loligo, Sepia, Octopus","c":"Cnidaria-Bonellia, Physalia, Aurelia","d":"Porifera-Spongilla, Euplectella, Pennatula","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"On the basis of organisation, animals are grouped into:","a":"Metazoa and cumetazoa","b":"Protozoa and metazoa","c":"Parazoa and metazoa","d":"Protozoa and parazoa","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"In coelomates, the problem of diffusion of food from gut to tissues is solved by:","a":"the presence of coelomic fluid.","b":"churning the food within the body cavity.","c":"developing a circulatory system.","d":"developing gut associated glands.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"An animal having diploblastic acoelomic condition is:","a":"Ascaris","b":"sea anemone","c":"Planaria","d":"Periplaneta","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The adults are radially symmetrical but larvae exhibit bilateral symmetry in:","a":"Mollusca","b":"Hemichordata","c":"Echinodermata","d":"Cephalochordata","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic feature of kingdom animalia?","a":"Storage of carbohydrates as starch","b":"Multicellularity","c":"Obtaining nutrients by ingestion","d":"Having eukaryotic cells without walls","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Cleavage in mammals is:","a":"Holoblastic equal","b":"Holoblastic unequal","c":"Superficial","d":"Discoidal","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Jaws are absent in:","a":"Protochordata","b":"Protochordata and cyclostomata","c":"Amphioxus and Balanoglossus.","d":"Herdmania and Myxine","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following pairs of animals are 14. similar to each other pertaining to the feature stated against them?","a":"Pteropus and Ornithorhyncus - Viviparity","b":"Garden lizard and crocodile Three chambered heart","c":"Ascaris and Ancylostoma Metameric segmentation","d":"Sea horse and flying fish Cold blooded (poikilothermal)","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Millipede (Julus) and Centipede (Scolopendra) are both included under:","a":"Arachnida","b":"Myriapoda","c":"Scaphopoda","d":"Pelecypoda","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The following statement are associated with the occurrence statement of notochord Identify the incorrect","a":"It is present only in larval tail in ascidians.","b":"It is replaced by a vertebral column in adult frog.","c":"It is absent throughout the life in humans from the very beginning.","d":"It is present throughout life in Amphioxus.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"In which of the following animal, post anal tail is found?","a":"Earthworm","b":"Lower invertebrate","c":"Scorpion","d":"Snake","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"A rhabditiform larva is formed in the life cycle of:","a":"Ascaris","b":"Tapeworm","c":"Hydra","d":"Leucosolenia","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Sense organs of Aurelia are:","a":"Tentacle","b":"Tentaculocyst","c":"Nematocyst","d":"Otolith","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Book-lungs are found in:","a":"Myriapoda","b":"Crustacea","c":"Arachnida","d":"Insecta","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"In animals of which class, the number of body segments is definite?","a":"Oligochaeta","b":"Hirudinaria","c":"Polychaeta","d":"None of these","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following sets of animals give birth to young ones?","a":"Platypus, Penguin, Bat, Hippopotamus","b":"Shrew, Bat, Cat, Kiwi","c":"Kangaroo, Hedgehog, Dolphin, Loris","d":"Lion, Bat, Whale, Ostrich","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Syncytial epidermis occurs in:","a":"Ascaris","b":"Hydra","c":"Taenia","d":"Leucosolenia","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"In which of the following classes, locomotory organs are absent?","a":"Rhizopoda","b":"Sporozoa","c":"Suctoria","d":"Mastigophora","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which one of the following animals possesses  nerve cells but no nerves?","a":"Hydra","b":"Tapeworm","c":"Earthworm","d":"Planaria","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Locomotion in Kangaroo is:","a":"Volant","b":"Saltatorial","c":"Cursorial","d":"Graviportal","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"A student has identified a triploblastic coelomate segmented animal as an arthropod. Which additional character the student should have verified before identifying that animal as an arthropod","a":"Presence of wings","b":"Presence of antenna","c":"Type of coelom","d":"Type of symmetry","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Medusa of Obelia is:","a":"Carnivorous","b":"Herbivorous","c":"Detritus feeder","d":"Omnivorous","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Elephantiasis is caused by:","a":"Trichinella","b":"Desmoscolex","c":"Enterobius","d":"Wuchereria","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"What is the true for mammalia?","a":"Platypus is oviparous.","b":"Bats have feather.","c":"Elephant is an ovo-viviparous.","d":"Diaphragm is absent.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which group of vertebrates comprises the highest number of endangered species?","a":"Mammals.","b":"Fishes","c":"Reptiles","d":"Birds","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which character is not same in aves and mammals?","a":"Single systemic arch","b":"Metanephric kidney","c":"Homoiotherms","d":"Seven cervical vertebrae","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following traits is not shared by both sea anemones and jellyfish?","a":"A medusa as the dominant stage in the life cycle.","b":"Possession of a gastro-vascular cavity.","c":"Sexual reproduction.","d":"Nematocysts present on the tentacles,","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following is not the common fundamental feature for animal classification?","a":"Germinal layers","b":"Pathway of water transport","c":"Pattern of organisation of cells","d":"Serial repetition of the segments","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Hemichordates have now been placed with the non-chordates, close to echinoderms, because true ","a":"notochord is absent.","b":"pharyngeal gill-slits are lacking.","c":"dorsal nerve cord is absent.","d":"heart is lacking.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Choanocytes perform:","a":"Nutrition.","b":"Excretion","c":"Reproduction","d":"Secretion of spicules","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following is deuterostomate and enterocoelomate invertebrate?","a":"Pila","b":"Ascaris","c":"Aphrodite","d":"Asterias","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following is a living fossil?","a":"Latimeria","b":"Lamprey","c":"Shark","d":"Eel","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"\"Portuguese man of war\" is;","a":"soldier of world war I","b":"portuguese soldier","c":"a sponge","d":"a polymorphic, colonial, colenterata","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following snake is not poisonous?","a":"Naja-naja","b":"Python","c":"Bungarus","d":"Hydrophis","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Crustacean which show commensalism with some coelenterates is:","a":"Cypris","b":"Hippa","c":"Crab","d":"Eupagurus","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Example of living fossil in arthropoda is:","a":"CimexTriarthrus","b":"Triarthrus","c":"Peripatus","d":"Eupagurus","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following characteristic is probably most responsible for the great diversification of insects on land?","a":"Segmentation","b":"Antennae","c":"Bilateral symmetry","d":"Exoskeleton","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which one of the following is a cartilaginous fish?","a":"Silver fish","b":"Dog fish","c":"Cray fish","d":"Star fish","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following endoparasite of man is viviparous?","a":"Ascaris","b":"Wuchereria","c":"Taenia","d":"Dracunculus","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following endoparasite of man is viviparous?","a":"Ascaris","b":"Wuchereria","c":"Taenia","d":"Dracunculus","hint":"","correct":"b"}]